This is Detective Jack Mosley. Shield number 227.
我是傑克.莫斯裡探員 編號227
I guess this will be my last will and testament.
我想這將是我最後的遺言
This is for Diane.
這是給戴安的
When this day is over, they're gonna come and talk to you about this...
今天一切結束之後 他們就會去找你把事情告訴你
...and they're gonna... They're gonna tell you what happened, Diane.
然後他們會... 他們會告訴你發生了什麼，戴安
But what they tell you is not really what happened here.
但是他們所說得，並不是真正發生的事實
So I hope that you get this.
所以，我希望你可以聽到這些話
I was trying to do a good thing.
我是想做一件好事
Police! Get down! Everybody, down!
警察！趴下！全部都趴下！
Down! Get down!
趴下！趴下！
Go, go, go! Come on!
走，進去，進去！快點！
- Clear. - Police. Get down.
- 沒人 - 是警察， 給我趴下
Seal it off.
給我封鎖出口
Agent 10-10, we're all secure.
這裡一切安妥了
All right, we're out of here.
好了，我們收隊吧
It's clear.
一切正常
You smell that?
你聞到那陣味了嗎？
Couple hours. We gotta move now. Would you turn that thing off?
死了幾個小時，我們得抓緊時間了 你能不能把那東西關掉？
All right, who's downstairs we don't need?
好了，樓下的哪個我們用不著的？
It's all yours. Good luck.
都交給你了，好運
I hate to do this, Jack, but I need you to sit on this until uniforms get here.
我也不想這樣，傑克 但我需要你留在這兒，等法醫來
- All right. - Just hang until you're relieved.
- 好的 - 他們來了你就可以走了
All right.
好的
Don't touch anything.
別碰任何東西
Any word on the suspects?
嫌犯說了什麼嗎？
- What do you want me to tell you? - What did you tell them?
- 你想要我告訴你什麼？ - 你跟他們說了什麼？
I saw someone out there.
我看到有人在外面
Yeah, yeah. Come on.
好，好，過來
- Anything for me? - Breath mints.
- 有什麼東西給我嗎？ - 口氣清新劑
Sergeant Cannova called. Wants you to write up this wire request.
加諾瓦警官打來電話 他要你幫他填好這張匯款單
Said to make sure you get the right dates on them.
他讓你這次不要再把日期搞錯了
The particulars are on your desk, and he needs it by tonight.
具體的事項放在你桌上了 他今天晚上就要
All right.
好的
All right, well, we can have an officer come by about 8 a.m. Tomorrow.
好，明天早上8點，我們可以派一個警官去
You gave her two?
你給她說派兩個人過去？
Well, you know, we do what we can.
你知道，我們只做我們力所能及的
Hey, Jack, I forgot to tell you, the lieutenant's looking for you.
嗨，傑克，忘了告訴你 中尉在找你
He wants you to find him right away.
他要你馬上去找他
Yeah, yeah.
知道了，知道了
Well, listen. All right, well, I'll call you.
嗯，聽著 好了，我等會兒再聯繫你
Hey, Mosley.
嗨，莫斯裡
- Mosley. - Yeah.
- 莫斯裡. - 嗯
Grace tell you to find me?
格麗絲有沒有讓你找我？
- Yeah, just a minute ago. - All right, need a favor.
- 是的，一分鐘前 - 好的，幫我個忙
Get this guy from lockup and run him to Centre Street.
把這個人從拘留所押到中心大街
The DA needs him ASAP. He's gotta be in front of a grand jury before 10.
檢察官要他馬上去 他必須在十點前到法庭上作證
I signed out.
我已經下班了
You signed the sheet?
你已經簽出了？
Well, not technically, no. But I mean, I'm signed out.
還沒有,但是我馬上就要去 我已經下班了
Then consider yourself on overtime.
那就當加班吧
Captain Gruber called. We need this thing done.
古博隊長打來電話 我們一定要把這件事情辦好
Don't you got some mutt that takes care of this?
你手下沒有什麼別的人可以做這件事情？
I got Keenan, but he's still on the Verrazano. He's behind some overturned truck.
有基南，但是他還在辦亞利桑那的那件案子 翻車的那件事
I'm tired. I mean, look, normally, you know me, I don't say no.
我很累了，你知道，一般來說 我不會拒絕你的
I know you been working all night, Jack...
我知道你忙了一晚上，傑克...
...but who's the detective and who's the lieutenant here?
但這裡誰說了算？
I mean, Jack, I got nobody else.
我是想說，傑克，我沒有別人可以做這件事了
It's a nothing thing.
這不是什麼大不了的事情
One hundred and eighteen minutes to get a little hemorrhoid 16 blocks.
就花兩個小時，過16個街區
I'll let you come in to work late tomorrow.
你明天可以晚點上班
Yeah, yeah.
好吧，好吧
Edward Bunker.
愛德華.本克
Yeah, that's me, officer. Eddie Bunker, right here.
嗨，警官，是我 我就是愛迪.本克
Down here, the last cell.
在這裡，最裡面的一間
- Come back in an hour. - What do you mean, come back?
- 你過一個小時再來吧 - 你什麼意思，過一會兒再來？
He's supposed to wear a suit when he leaves.
他要穿好西裝才能走
- And? - It's not here yet.
- 然後？ - 西裝還沒有送到
Just get him out here, all right?
現在就把他給我弄出來，好不好？
They said he'd wear a suit.
他們說，他一定要穿西裝
No, yeah, I'm supposed to get a suit. It's a three-piece suit. It's gray.
不，對，我應該穿西裝 是三件式的，灰色的
It's got... Wait. Yeah.
是... 等等，呃
It's a three-button, it's gray, it's got cuffs on the pants.
是三鈕式的，灰色的 褲子是翹邊的
They brought the catalog down. I picked it out of the catalog.
他們給我帶來了樣本目錄 我從裡面選了一件
I'm not supposed to leave without it. Wait.
我不穿西裝，不能走的，等等
I'm not supposed to leave without that suit.
我不能不穿西裝就走
- You tell it to him. - No, that's why you brought my shoelaces.
- 你自己跟他說 - 你不能讓他這樣做的
- Come on, come on. - I'm not supposed to.
- 來來，過來 - 我不能就這樣出去
- Yo, yo, you take the old lady, right? - Yeah, you sure?
- 喂，你說的那個故事，你會帶老婦人走的，對嗎？ - 嗯，你肯定？
The old lady goes into the car, otherwise she dies.
一定要讓老婦人上車，不然她就死定了
- You think so? - Yeah, man.
- 確定？ - 我是這樣想的
That's what... I don't know. You gotta figure out the answer for yourself.
你再想想看呢？
Everybody just calm down. Officer, I'm going to court.
兩位警官，你們聽我說，我要去上法庭
- I'm supposed to have a suit. - Hey.
- 我需要一套西裝才能上庭 - 喂
Shut up. Here's your property.
給我閉嘴，這是你的東西
- It's not a good sign. - Hands behind your back.
- 這不是個好兆頭. - 把手放在你的背後
- Hold on, I'm trying...
- 等等，我還要... - 手放到後面來
I don't even have my... All my prop... Wait one minute.
我還沒有我的... 所有我的東西... 就等一分鐘
It's not right. They promised me the suit.
這樣不對 他們答應給我一件西裝的
I picked it out of the catalog... Wait, my book.
我從目錄裡面挑出來了一件的 等等，我的書
I can't leave without my book. My book is very important to me.
這本書可不能掉了，對我來說，他很重要
Why are we rushing like this? It's not a good sign.
你這麼著急幹什麼？這不是個好兆頭
- Hey. - What's the damn answer?
- 喂 - 到底是怎麼個結果？
- Hey! - Shut up.
- 喂！ - 閉嘴！
- I hate police. - Half a tank.
- 我討厭警察 - 汽油還有一半
You could have had a little more patience.
你就不能再等一會？
This suit don't mean nothing to you. You probably got a bunch of suits.
這套西裝可以對你來說沒什麼 你大概有一堆西裝
But it's a whole different thing to me.
但是對我卻非同小可
These cars don't ever change, huh?
警車怎麼都是這種樣式？
Traditional cruisers.
總是這一種車型
And the same retarded hump in the middle.
座位設計不合理
Smell the same way, like Lysol and vomit.
味道也總是那麼難聞
I hope nobody vomited back here. They probably did.
這種味道讓人嘔吐 估計有人已經吐過
Hey, man, let me ask you something.
喂，老兄，問你個問題
I'm trying to figure this out.
我在想一個問題
You driving along in your hurricane, right?
你正在路上開車，突然刮起了龍捲風
There's three people at the bus stop.
有三個人在路邊
Yeah, one is an old lady. She's sick, she about to die.
一個是老奶奶，她病了，就快死了
The second one is your best friend.
第二個是你最好的朋友
He saved your life, right?
他救過你的命
And the third is the girl of your dreams.
第三個是你的夢中情人
Right, but check it out...
然後，是這樣的...
...you only got space in the car for one person.
你的車只能再坐下一個人
Right? Who you take?
就這樣，你會讓誰上車？
It's a riddle that's supposed to tell what type of person you are...
這可以說是一個性格測試
...like where you at in your life.
可以看出你是怎樣一個人
It's a hypothetical question, man, damn.
你用不著這麼嚴肅吧，老兄，只是一個假設
It's just a hypothetical...
只是個假設而已
Well, good. Fine, good. I guess that's my answer.
好吧，好吧 我猜我知道你的答案了
Why don't you get on the loudspeaker?
你為什麼不開擴音警笛？
Put the Hawaii Five-0 light on or something.
或者把警燈打開？
Use your police power. Put on a little siren.
顯示一下你們警察的權威 按一按警笛
Make room, make a hole.
讓前面的車子都讓開
Isn't that the saying, "Make a hole, make a hole"?
你們警察不是最喜歡說，「閃開，閃開」？
Go on, make a hole.
讓他們靠邊啊！
Signs. Everywhere, signs, signs, signs. All over, man.
徵兆，到處都是，都是徵兆，徵兆啊 處處都是
I used to not even see nothing like that, man.
我以前注意不到它們的
And then I start seeing them. And I start looking for them.
後來我慢慢能夠看到一些
And everything just start falling in place.
到最後我發現一切是注定的
I'm gonna be all right, where I'm supposed to be.
我會沒事的，直覺告訴我
I ain't got my suit, but once they get my testimony...
雖然沒拿到我的西裝 但一旦作證完畢
...they drop my charges, I'm free.
他們就會撤消對我的指控，我就自由了
It's making sense to me.
我覺得這是合理的
I believe in that.
我相信一定會那樣的
Being in the right place.
這是我的命
Being where you supposed to be. You believe in that?
你相信命運麼？
I believe life's too long and guys like you make it even longer.
我相信人生太漫長 而且有你這種人，讓我更受煎熬
Life's too long?
太漫長？
Damn.
你不是說真的吧
That's some cold shit, man. I ain't never heard nobody say no shit like that.
我從來沒聽人說過這樣的話
Usually you hear about people trying to make their life longer, you know?
人們總是想活得長點，你說對吧？
Trying to stay alive a little longer. You sound a little...
而且他們用盡一切辦法活得久一些 你看上去有點...
...depressed or something, you all right?
有點悲觀，你還好嗎？
You stopping?
你為什麼停下了？
This ain't the courthouse, man. What you doing?
這裡不是法院，老兄 你在幹什麼？
Yo.
喂
Yo, why you stopping?
喂，你為什麼停車？
You gonna rush me out to court, and now you stopping? What are you...?
你應該送我去法院 你幹嘛？
Hey. Hey, man.
嗨，嗨，老兄
Hey, man. Listen, man, I got an important appointment after my court date, man.
嗨，老兄，聽我說， 我上庭之後還有一個重要的約會
That shit ain't funny, man. Come on, man. It's not a game, man.
不要和我開玩笑 拜託，老兄，這可不是做遊戲
Yo.
喂
Some bullshit, man.
該死的
Hey. Hey!
喂，喂！
No, man. It ain't Miller Time, man.
哦，不，你可太不負責了
The weather will be clear early morning, but the rest of the day...
上午天氣很晴朗 但是下午...
Sam. Hey, Angela.
山姆，安吉娜，你們好！
So we are looking at a hot, humid day.
總的來說，今天會是悶熱而潮濕的一天
Looks like temperature might reach 100 degrees...
氣溫可能會攀升到100度
...so don't forget to pack your sunscreen.
所以出門的時候，別忘了帶你的防曬油
Add a pack of these, will you?
給我個袋子裝起來，好嗎？
I know this dude smelled funny. I got the wrong dude, man.
我就覺得這個老兄奇奇怪怪 真是倒霉
17.50. What?
17塊5
Hey, don't open it. Come over here.
嗨，先別開，來，拿過來
What time is it, man?
都幾點了
It's 8:11.
8:11了
That's a good sign. That's a good sign.
還好，還好
I'm on my way. I'm gonna get there.
我都上路了，我一定會準時到法院的
- Want change? - No, you keep the change.
- 要找零？ - 不，不用找了
Keep the change. All right, you have a good day.
不用找了 好的，一切順利
- I don't want the peanuts. - Bye.
- 我不要花生 - 拜拜
No, man. Can't do nothing for you, understand?
不，老兄，我什麼也幫不了你，明白？
Hey, you better give me that change. I'm gonna need that.
嗨，你還是把那找錢給我吧 我可能需要點零鈔
You see my situation right here?
你自己看看吧？
No, no, no! No, no, no!
不，不，不！
Hey!
嗨！
How am I supposed to get out?
我怎麼出去啊？
- Come on. - Help me. Help me.
- 快點 - 幫幫我，幫幫我
- My book. Why did you stop? - Go, left, go. Left.
- 我的書！告訴你別停下的！ - 左邊，快跑
Move. Move. Move.
快，快，快！
Wait. Freeze!
等等，停下！
In here. Come on.
到裡面去，快點
Shit.
該死的
Hey!
喂！
Just get out of here, now! Go on. Go!
快點給我滾開，走開！
Come on, let's go. That way, let's go. Go, go.
來，我們走 那邊，快，快
Ready? Here.
這邊
Let's go. Go.
快點走
- Dominic, get people out of here, right now. - Jesus, Jackie. What's going on?
- 多米尼克，讓你的人現在就出去 - 老天呢，傑克，怎麼回事？
- Everybody. You too. - All right, okay.
- 所有人，包括你，都給我出去 - 好的好的
- Let's go. - Come on, come on, come on.
- 我們走 - 來，快點走
Come on, keep going. Come on. Come on, move it.
快點，別停下，快點出去
Yeah, this is Detective Jack Mosley, shield number 227.
喂，我是傑克.莫斯裡探員 編號227
I am 10-13, at... Hold on a minute.
這裡有緊急情況，地址是...等等
- Dominic, what's the address here? - 133 Mulberry.
- 多米尼克,這裡地址是什麼？ - 毛布裡大街133號
133 Mulberry.
毛布裡大街133號
Mulberry Street.
毛布裡大街
All right.
好
Is they coming?
他們什麼時候能到?
I don't know why you stopped, man.
我真是不明白，你為什麼剛剛要停車?
I don't know why you would do that, man.
我真是搞不懂
They said you were nobody.
他們說你是個小毛賊
- I ain't nobody. - Shut up.
- 顯然不是這樣的 - 閉嘴
You a wino. You need to stop drinking, that's what you need.
你這酒鬼，你不能再喝了，知道麼?
Shut up.
給我閉嘴
Jack?
傑克？
- Frank. - Hey.
- 弗蘭克 - 嗨
You all right?
你還好嗎？
- Yeah. - Yeah?
嗯
We were on Mott when the call went out. Heard it was you.
我們在無線電上聽到你的呼救
Got here as soon as we could.
我們就盡快過來了
Oh, hi.
哦，你好
- Hey. - You all right?
- 嗨 - 你還好嗎？
- Yeah, I'm all right. - You having fun?
- 嗯，我還行 - 好玩嗎？
- No. - No? Oh, well.
- 不 - 不？那好吧
Gotta have fun.
應該挺刺激的
- What's up, Jack? - Hey, man. Hi.
- 怎麼了，傑克？ - 嘿，老弟，嗨
You did a really great, great job, man.
你做得很好，很不錯，老兄
You got yourself a bad guy.
你幹掉了第一個殺手
Been a while, huh? Yeah.
有一陣子沒這樣了，是吧？
We got the second shooter half a block from here, so it's done.
我們在一個街區之外，抓到了第二個槍手 所以，一切都結束了
- Sure you're okay? - Yeah.
- 你肯定你沒事？ - 我沒事
I'm just getting my wind. I was running.
我一路跑過來，只是有點累
Why don't you let us take it from here.
接下來的事情，讓我們來處理吧
Oh, yeah.
你們應該這樣做
We'll get the kid where he belongs, and you don't have to worry about a thing.
我們知道怎麼處理這小子的事情 你什麼也不用擔心
- We'll get you home. - Yes, please.
- 你回家吧 - 對，拜託你們了
Please, please, officer. That's a very good idea...
求你了，求你了，長官 這個主意太好了
...because, honestly, I don't think this dude is doing too good.
因為，老實說，我真的覺得這老兄不行
I told him not to stop.
我跟他說了，別停車
I asked him not to stop. He just had to stop.
我給他說不要停車，可是他不聽
That's when everything happened. Dude came to the window.
然後那個人就走到我車窗邊
I have a very important appointment aft...
我上庭之後還有一個很重要的約會呢
Jack.
傑克
Hey, Shue.
舒，你好
Come on. Here.
來，給你
Why don't you take this. Come on.
拿著這個，來
We'll get you out of here. Got a car waiting. All right?
我們送你回家，門口有輛車
Get some sleep.
回家好好睡一覺
Jack?
傑克？
The kid was gonna testify against Jerry.
這小子要指證傑瑞
He saw Jerry doing some business.
他看到了傑瑞的一些事情
Now, we both know that Jerry has never been a standup guy like you and me.
我們都知道，傑瑞不會像你我一樣那麼靠得住
He'll roll over, they indict him. We can't have that.
他什麼都會說出來 我們不能讓那樣的事情發生
No. It's gonna hurt a lot of us.
那樣會牽涉到我們中的很多人
Come on.
過來
See, this whole thing caught us... It caught us completely unaware.
其實本來不該由你來送他去法庭的
It was supposed to be Teach's nephew driving him.
本來是由Teach的外甥來開車送他
But he got stuck out there in traffic, who knows where...
但是他因為塞車，沒趕上
...so then your lieutenant, he pegged you.
結果你上司就讓你去了
You know, just the wrong time and the wrong place for you today.
今天發生的一切 都只是因為錯誤的時間，錯誤的地點
All right. Now, you know that I would never put you in a position like this, right?
僅此一次，下不為例 你也知道我從來沒有這樣為難過你，對吧？
You know that, huh?
你可以理解，對吧？
And I never figured you'd cap one of those guys.
我也沒想到他們會失手
- That's what I get for hiring drug addicts. - Grab the gun.
- 他媽的一群癮君子 - 拿住槍
Grab the gun. There you go.
就是那樣
Come on. Frank?
就這樣，弗蘭克
- Here we go. - All right, here we go. Jack.
- 好了 - 好了，動手吧，傑克
Squeeze the trigger.
扳扳機
All right. Let go of the gun. Let go of the gun.
好了，放開槍，快鬆手
I figure it like this.
我幫你想好了一個借口
You... You pop the guys trying to spring the kid.
你幹掉了那幾個殺手後
The kid, well, he gets your gun.
這小子趁你不注意搶了你的槍
And he takes you hostage.
然後還把你當人質
So we came in and saved the day.
然後我們出現，搞定一切
He died, you lived.
他死了，你沒有
Now, this could be a good thing for you, Jack.
我覺得這樣不錯，傑克
Get you back where you belong.
對大家都好交代
- Are you still with...? - Stand up.
- 你還跟那個誰在一起嗎？ - 給我站起來
- You still with what's-her-name? - Come on, stand up.
- 她叫什麼來的？ - 站起來
- What are you waiting for? - What's her name?
- 快啊 - 她叫什麼名字？
Caroline.
凱羅琳
It's Caroline.
她叫凱羅琳
This changes everything, Jack.
這下一切都不一樣了，傑克
Over here.
站到那邊去
Come on, Frank.
快點，弗蘭克
Kid, get up. Come on.
小子，起來，快點
Shit. Man, shit.
天哪
All right, Jack, it's 8:25.
傑克，已經8:25了
- You stay there. - Listen to me, the jury's tenure ends at 10.
- 你給我站住別動 - 你聽我說，陪審團最多等到10點
All right? The kid gets there one minute past, all this...
這小子只要遲到一分鐘，這一切...
...it doesn't matter.
你做的一切就白做了
And all you gotta do is look the other way.
你再仔細想想
All right? We still got options here.
好嗎？一切都還好商量
Okay?
好嗎？
We just want the kid.
我們只要那個小子
Jack, Jack, Jack, just let me help you.
傑克啊傑克，我可是在幫你
All right?
好不好？
Back up.
你給我退後
Jack, once you go out that door...
傑克，一旦你走出那扇門...
...I can't help you.
我就幫不了你了
Please just back up, Frank. Just back up.
麻煩你退後，弗蘭克 退後
He shot a cop.
他對警察開槍
What the hell did you see? What did you see?
你到底看到了些什麼？ 看到了什麼？
That cop back there.
剛才那個警察
I seen him around my way...
我有次碰巧看到他...
...holding a gun in this little Puerto Rican kid's mouth.
他把槍塞到那個可憐的波多黎各人的嘴裡
Come on. Let's go.
快點，我們快點離開這裡
He said he'd kill his mother if he testified.
他說，如果他出庭指證，就會殺了他的母親
What you doing that for? We need that.
你那是幹嗎？我們需要那支槍
The shell in that gun was over 20 years old. Lucky it went off at all.
那支槍已經有20年歷史了 剛剛是我們運氣，它居然還管用
- They didn't tell you Shue was a cop? - No, they didn't tell me.
- 他們沒有告訴你舒是個警察？ - 不，他們沒有告訴過我
They showed me a picture, that was it.
他們只是給我看他的一張照片
Well, congratulations, because you're about to testify against one of New York's worst.
這下好，恭喜你 因為你和紐約最陰暗的一面開戰了
- What? - Fellas, look, the clock's ticking.
- 什麼？ - 兄弟們，時間在一秒秒過去
He's gotta be at the courthouse by 10. We know where he's going.
他們必須在十點之前到達法院 我們知道他們的目的地
Mulvey, you're coming with me.
毛利，你跟我來
- Know where you're going? - Take the north side.
- 知道你們該幹什麼了麼？ - 我負責北邊
- You got it, let's go. - Come on.
- 明白了，我們走 - 快點
- Captain. - Where are we, Frank?
- 上尉 - 怎麼樣了，弗蘭克？
Well, we're putting descriptions out over precinct channels.
我們還沒有讓別區的人知道這件事情 只有本轄區的人知道大致情況
No names, or that one's a cop. It'll help to have some eyes.
沒有指明姓名，或者說其中一個是警察
- How long can you sit on this? - He shot a cop.
- 這件事，你能瞞多久？ - 他可開槍射擊了一個警察！
You're the precinct captain, Dan. How long?
你是這個轄區的老大啊，丹 多久？
I don't know. Hour, maybe a little more.
我不知道，一小時，可能更短些
- Who's on this with you? - My guys.
- 都是什麼人和你一起處理這件事？ - 都是我們的人
Ortiz and Maldonado from the 66. Touhey and Kaller from the 111.
66分隊的奧蒂斯跟馬多納多 111分隊的圖西和凱樂
A couple others you don't wanna know about.
還有一些你也沒興趣知道
The guy was your partner for 20 years.
那個人做了你搭檔20年了
What the hell happened in there?
他很清楚我們的做事方法 他到底是怎麼了？
- Is he drunk? - I don't know.
- 他是不是喝醉了？ - 我不知道
I don't know. We woke him up.
我真的不知道
Hopefully he'll do what he always does, and we can go back to work.
希望他別多管閒事 這樣我們大家都可以相安無事
If he doesn't?
如果他不呢？
We gotta quash this thing before he gets his legs back.
那我們要先下手為強，主動出擊
These are his streets.
這裡是他的地盤
This could get ugly for all of us if that kid talks.
如果那小子開口，我們就慘了
- He can't talk. - He won't talk.
- 他不能說 - 他不會說的
Look, I appreciate what you did for me back there...
你看，我很感激前面你為我做的一切
...but I'm starting to think you're not the dude for this.
但是我在想，你可能不適合送我去法院
I mean, you're out of breath, you're hung-over.
我是說，你上氣不接下氣，還喝醉了
Your leg is gonna give out on you any second, man.
你說不定什麼時候就倒下去了，老兄
I got someplace I need to be at 12, you understand?
我十二點一定要赴那個約，你明白嗎？
I need to be finished at court by 10...
所以十點前，我一定要結束法院的事情
...or I'm not gonna get where I'm supposed to get.
不然我就肯定會失約
- You understand what I'm saying? - All right, I understand.
- 你明白我在說什麼嗎？ - 好了，我明白了
- You're not listening to what I'm saying. - Wait, come here. Come here.
- 你根本沒聽我在說什麼 - 等等，這邊，這邊走
Come on.
快點
Hung-over.
醉酒
A bad leg.
腿受傷了
No gun.
沒槍
- Bobby? - Yeah?
- 波比？ - 在
- You thinking what I'm thinking? - I'm already there.
- 你知道我在懷疑哪個地方了麼？ - 我知道了
Oh, God.
天哪
Come on, let's go.
快點，我們進去
Listen, just stay put right here. I'll be right back.
聽著，你在這裡站著別動 我很快回來
Come on, man, don't take long. We gotta go.
快點，別太久了，我們必須馬上走
Hurry up.
抓緊點
- Hey, man, where your bathroom? - What?
- 你洗手間在哪裡？ - 什麼？
Your bathroom. Where your bathroom at?
洗手間在哪裡？
Down at the end of the hall.
走廊盡頭
Yeah.
好的
That's what you look like when you smile, huh?
你笑起來原來是這樣
You was probably drinking then too.
可能也是喝醉了
There's the lady.
終於看到個女人
Redhead. She cute. That ain't bad.
紅頭髮，很可愛，很不錯
Hey, man. Come on, don't be stopping to get high or nothing like that.
老兄，快點，別停下來
Man, we gotta go.
我們得快點離開這裡
Make sure you lift the seat up before you go.
記住把廁板提起來
It's up already.
已經提起來了
Maybe you left it like that, huh?
你已經提起來了啊
I'm coming.
我要來了
Hey, Jack.
嗨，傑克
Jack Mosley.
傑克.莫斯裡
Why did you do that?
你為什麼那樣做？
Do what?
做什麼？
Shoot that cop.
對那個警察開槍
Cops...
警察
...they don't shoot other cops.
應該不會對自己人開火
Especially over nobody like me.
尤其不會為了我這種小毛賊
It's a long way to go for a stranger, you know.
而且你並不認識我，你能這樣做真是不容易
Thank you.
謝謝你
I never had nobody...
從來沒有一個人...
Hell, man, you know.
該死的，你知道的
I don't rock with the police, you know what I'm saying?
我從來就不喜歡警察 你知道我的意思麼？
- Finger off the trigger. - They never been my friend.
- 放開扳機 - 他們從來不是我的朋友
- Then here you come. - On the ground.
- 然後你出現了 - 把槍扔到地上
It's kind of bugging me out, you know.
可是你和其他人不同
You on some vigilante business.
你不像其他的警察
Let's go.
這邊走
- Jack... - Put your arms around the pole.
- 傑克 - 兩手抱住這柱子
I don't know what to think anymore.
我都有點懷疑自己了
- Here. Cuff yourself. - What are you doing, Jack?
- 用這個，給自己銬上 - 你在幹什麼，傑克？
Yeah, it's a little strange.
是啊，這是有些奇怪
You know? By any definition, this here.
你知道麼？這一切都讓我有點不解
All right, kid. Good.
夠了，小子，做得好
Okay.
好的
Okay, okay, okay.
好了，好了，好了
You should have done what you always do, Jack.
你不該這樣做的，傑克， 你應該像你以前那樣
- Where's your phone? - It's on the left-hand side.
- 你手機呢？ - 在左邊口袋裡
They know I'm here. If I don't answer it...
他們知道我來了這裡 如果我不接的話
- Jack? - Let's go, kid. Come on.
- 傑克？ - 我們走，小子，快點
- Bob. - Bob's a little tied up right now, Frank.
- 鮑勃 - 鮑勃現在不方便講電話，弗蘭克
All right, I'm impressed, Jack.
好了，傑克，你很讓我吃驚
Did you shoot him too?
你也對他開槍了麼？
Send someone to check on Bobby.
派人去救波比
Jack, you're not up to this.
傑克，你不會成功的
All right? It's gonna end bad for you.
知道嗎？你不會有好結果的
You lost the kid, didn't you?
那小子跑了，對吧？
He bailed on you. Well, you know what?
他把你甩了？好吧，你知道嗎...
That is the best thing that could have happened.
這是最理想的情況了
So why don't you go home.
我建議你回家
Forget about what happened.
忘掉所有的一切
We'll take it from here. Are you looking for him?
剩下的我們來處理
And you can't find him.
你一個人是找不到他的
We're gonna find him, all right?
我們會找到他，知道嗎？
We're gonna find him.
我們會找到他
All right, Jack, now you can hang up.
好了，傑克，現在你可以掛電話了
Where are you, kid?
你小子跑哪裡去了？
All right. Now, let's see which way he went.
好吧，現在，我們好好想想他會跑到哪裡去
Did he go up? Did he go down?
他是要坐巴士，還是要搭地鐵？
In or out, Jackie. Which way did he go?
在街上還是藏在哪裡？他逃去哪裡了？
Let's see if he went down.
我們來看看他是不是去了地鐵站
- Excuse me, sir, do you mind swiping? - Get a job, man.
- 麻煩，先生，你能幫我刷一下卡嗎？ - 去找個工作，兄弟
Ma'am, would you mind swiping me in?
夫人，你能刷卡讓我進去嗎？
Ma'am? Ma'am, would you mind swiping me in, please, ma'am?
夫人？夫人，你能刷卡讓我進去嗎？ 求你了，夫人
I have a very important appointment I have to...
我有一個非常重要的約會 我必須得...
Excuse me, ma'am, would you mind...? Somebody mind swiping me in?
麻煩你了，夫人，你能不能...？ 誰能幫忙刷卡讓我進去？
I'm trying to get to an important appointment.
我要趕個非常重要的約會
Somebody help me. Somebody help me.
誰幫幫我，誰幫幫我
Somebody help me.
誰幫幫我
Hey.
喂
Come here.
過來
- Come on. Go. - Thank you. Thank you very much.
- 來吧，從這裡走 - 謝謝，太謝謝了
Eddie!
愛迪！
- Oh, no. - What are you doing?
- 噢，不 - 你這是在幹什麼？
- Why are you running? - What do you want?
- 你為什麼逃走？ - 你想要什麼？
It's too much, man. I'm doing the rest on my own.
你已經做得夠多了，兄弟 接下來的我自己可以處理
I'm doing what I said. I'm getting out of here.
我在照我自己說的做 我要離開這裡
- Lf I can find you, they can find you! - I'm doing what I said.
- 如果我不找到你，他們會找到你 - 我在照我自己說的做
Eddie, listen to me. Listen to me. Listen to me!
愛迪， 聽我說，聽我說！
- I'm your only friend down here. - No, you're not my friend.
- 我是唯一可以幫助你的朋友 - 不，你不是我的朋友
- I can do this... - Friend? You don't even know me!
- 我能幫你... - 朋友？你根本不認識我！
And get me where? You gonna get me shot.
你帶我去哪裡？你會讓我吃子彈！
Ever since I've been with you, people been trying to shoot me. People you know!
自從你出現了，就有人要想幹掉我 你認識的人！
Look, man, I got someplace I need to be. I got something I need to do.
聽著，我有我必須去的地方 我有我必須做的事
Unless you gonna shoot me or arrest me, I'm going, Jack.
除非你殺了我或者逮捕我 我要走了，傑克
- I can't let you leave. - Thank you, Jack Mosley. I'm going.
- 我不能讓你走 - 謝謝你，傑克.莫斯裡，我走了
- You can't leave. - Yes, I can. Thank you, Jack Mosley.
- 你不能走 - 我能走，謝謝你，傑克 莫斯裡.
Stop. Don't do that. Stop.
不要這樣，停下來
Ladies and gentlemen...! You're not going. Come here.
你不能走，過來！
Eddie!
愛迪！
Okay, okay. Okay, we gotta go.
好，好，我跟你走
- Move! Move! - Get out of the way!
- 讓開！讓開！ - 別擋路！
Move! Move!
讓開！讓開！
- Here, come on. - What are you doing?
- 這邊，快點 - 你在幹什麼？
Taxi! Hey!
出租車！嘿！
Taxi!
出租車！
It's Kaller. He just missed them at the Canal Street station.
凱樂說他剛剛在加奈路讓他們給跑掉了
Where, where, where?
哪裡，哪裡，哪裡？
Shit. Where the hell is he?
媽的，你們到底在哪裡？
Goddamn it.
該死的
We're gonna find you.
我們會找到你們的
Yeah, this is Detective Nugent. I need a triangulation...
我是紐金探員，我需要你幫我定位一個手機
...on Detective Torres' cell phone. Area code (917) 935...
號碼是917-935...
That cop back at the apartment, he said you should do what you always do.
剛剛在你家的那個警察 他說你應該像你以前那樣做
What did he...? What did he mean by that?
他這樣說是什麼意思？
You're not doing what you always do, huh?
你沒有像你以前那樣做，對嗎？
Jack Mosley, I get it. I see the signs.
傑克.莫斯裡，我知道了 我預感到了
I'm where I'm supposed to be. I was wrong. You're the right guy.
這一切都是注定 我以前錯了，你是我命中的恩人
I could have got another guy, did something different, but I got you.
我有可能碰上另外一個人 他可能就不會像你這樣做了
I appreciate it. You're the right guy.
我很感激你，你可以幫助我
- Okay? - Okay.
- 知道嗎？ - 嗯
- This is Comtech, over. - Yeah, go, this is Nugent.
- 這裡是技術支援中心 - 對，我是紐金
GPS indicates they're on Bowery.
全球定位系統顯示他們在保利街
Repeat, Bowery, moving south towards Pell.
重複一遍，保利街 目標在向南靠近培爾街
Speed indicates they're on foot.
移動速度表明他們在步行
Are you hearing this, boys? He's in Chinatown.
大家聽到了嗎，他們在中國城
Let's move in.
我們都到那裡去
- What's the deal with that book? - It's my business plans.
- 你為什麼一直拿著那本書？ - 這是我的計劃書，我想做點小生意
I'm moving to Seattle. My sister's already living out there.
我要去西雅圖，我姐姐在那邊
I'm gonna open up a bakery. But it's only, like, a specialty bakery.
我要開一個糕點店，不是一般的那種
Birthday cakes for little kids. There's a lot of money in that.
我的店只為小朋友做生日蛋糕 這樣的店收入不錯
I'm gonna send you a big birthday cake on your birthday...
你過生日的話，我送你一個很大的生日蛋糕如何？
- I hate birthday cakes. - You hate birthday cakes?
- 我討厭生日蛋糕 - 你討厭生日蛋糕？
First thing that doesn't go your way...
首先這不是你
...you're gonna be slipping into Carol's Clip and Curl...
你會做的事情是偷偷闖入別人的理髮店
...and stealing all her hair-care products.
然後偷走所有護髮產品
Because you're a thief. And that's what you are, Eddie.
因為你只會是一個小偷，愛迪
- You're always gonna be a thief. - People can change, Jack.
- 你一直會是個小偷 - 人是可以改變的，傑克
- Days change, seasons change. Not people. - Yes, you do...
- 日子能改變，季節能改變，人不會 - 人可以改變
- People don't change, Eddie. - Yes, you do. I'll get you that cake.
- 人是不會變的，愛迪 - 會的，我會給你那個蛋糕的
You know what it's gonna say on top?
你知道蛋糕上會寫什麼嗎？
"Jack Mosley, ha-ha-ha, eat this." Make you eat your words, lick your fingers too.
"傑克 莫斯裡，哈哈哈，吃了這個" 你那時就知道你錯了
Subject's moving west on Pell.
目標沿培爾街向西移動
Subject now moving south on Doyers. Still moving south on Doyers.
目標現在上了道爾街，朝南移動 仍在道爾街上向南朝移動
Bobby, you take Doyer, we got Pell. And, Kaller, you close up Bowery.
波比，你走道爾街，我們從培爾街靠近 凱樂，你從保利街包抄
- Copy that. - Let's squeeze him.
- 收到 - 這下他們逃不掉了
- Copy that, on my way. - Why don't you pull up. Pull up.
- 把車停下
- Sorry. - Who is that? You can't go in here.
- 對不起 - 你們是誰？你們不能進去
Oh, sorry.
噢，對不起
Look, man, I gotta be down there. All right, you understand?
聽著，老兄，我們的方向是那邊 你明白嗎？
I gotta be down there that way, and there's streets and shit in between there.
我們應該下去，然後朝那個方向
You got some sort of plan? Some sort of police plan or something?
你有什麼計劃嗎？你不是警察麼？
I see your limp acting up. You ought to get that checked out.
我看你跛得越來越嚴重了 你應該去檢查一下
I have a buddy of mine walking around with a limp just like that.
我有個朋友 也像你這樣跛著腳走路
He don't wanna go to the doctor, though, right?
但他不願意看醫生
Finally he go, they say it's a fracture, right?
最後他不得不去看了 他們說這是骨折
And now it's infected. They gotta cut it off at the knee.
而且整條腿被感染了 膝蓋以下都得被截掉
Wasrt so bad, though. He had no more pain.
這樣也好，他不用那麼痛苦了
He ended up moving to Jersey, working for the PATH...
最後他去了新澤西州，找了一個工作
...being a motorman. Got a pension and shit now.
做火車司機，現在都他媽開始領養老金了
I guess everything happens for a reason, you know what I mean?
我認為每件事情都有它發生的原因 你懂我的意思嗎？
You're a sunny little shit, I'll give you that much.
你是個充滿幻想的人 這就是我對你的評價
Get in here! Get in that door!
進去！快進那扇門！
Jack!
傑克！
- Pull me in! Help me in! - Come on, come on, come on.
- 拉我進去！ - 快！
Lock the door.
把門鎖了
- Wait, wait, wait. - Hold up.
- 慢點，慢點 - 撐住
Come on.
快點
- You all right? - Yeah.
- 你沒事吧？ - 嗯
Jack, what are we doing? Where are we going?
傑克，我們在做什麼？我們要去哪裡？
- Come on. - Where we going, Jack?
- 快點 - 我們要去哪裡，傑克？
Out of the way.
讓開
Over here.
過來這裡
Jack? How we even know that Centre Street Courthouse is in this direction, Jack?
傑克，這個是朝中心大街法院的方向？
Jack? We gotta know...
傑克，確定是這個方向？
Down! Head down!
趴下！頭趴下！
Go!
走！
Come on!
快點！
Kaller!
凱樂！
Push it.
推開它！
You all right, Jack?
你還好吧，傑克？
I was aiming for the kid, if that makes you feel better.
我瞄準的是那個小子，不是你
Well, you missed!
那你沒射中！
That kid is gonna get you killed.
那小子會拖累死你的
He won'th that?
你覺得這樣值得麼？
Well, I got all day.
我可以一直這樣和你拖延下去
How about you, you got all day?
你呢，你有時間拖麼？
- Jack, you still there? - Yeah.
- 傑克，你還在嗎？ - 嗯
Still here.
還在
Well, this is awkward.
這有點棘手了
When I started this day...
今天早上我開始上班的時候
...I never figured on trading 9 mils with my friend.
沒有想到今天會和你開槍對射
I think we stopped being friends right around 8:25, in that bar.
我想在8:25，那個酒吧裡 我們就已經不是朋友了
No.
不
No, that's not gonna erase 20 years together.
那不能抹殺掉我們一起工作的20年
We're still friends.
我們仍然是朋友
Look...
聽著
...a lot I'd take back, but I can't.
我也後悔過許多以前做的事情 可是這些都不能挽回
Well, so you move forward. Next day, next case.
所以你只能向前看 新的一天，新的工作
- Lines were crossed. - What lines?
- 但是不能違背了原則 - 什麼原則？
- You hear me? Lines were crossed, Frank. - What lines? There are no lines!
- 你聽到了麼，不能違背原則 - 什麼原則？根本就沒有原則！
There's getting it done and not getting it done, period!
只有完成任務和完不成任務，就這樣！
You put the bad guys away no matter what it takes.
有時也許我們的方法很過分 但是我們也是在除暴安良
Now, you're gonna ruin the lives...
現在，你將犧牲...
...of six cops.
6個警察的生命
Good cops.
他們都是好警察
Good men.
善良的人
Are you ready to sacrifice their lives for that kid?
為了那個小子而犧牲掉他們，值得麼？
Hey, Frank.
弗蘭克
- Frank. - Yeah?
- 弗蘭克 - 嗯？
This is not about me ruining anybody's life.
我沒有想要犧牲任何人的生命
Okay? This is about you.
懂麼？而是因為你
You hear me?
聽到我說什麼嗎？
Yeah.
嗯
You look at that kid's jacket?
你看過那個小子紀錄了麼？
I did.
我看過
- Armed robbery, assault, beats old women... - I never had no armed robbery!
- 持械搶劫，侵犯他人，毆打老年婦女... - 我從來沒有持械搶劫過！
Beats old women over the heads, steals their Social Security checks.
為了搶去社保金，他毆打一位老年婦女
- One time, I used... - Shut up. Shut up.
- 只有一次，我曾經... - 閉嘴
Oh, no, don't tell him to shut up.
噢，不，不要叫他閉嘴
No, Jack, listen to him. No, that kid, he's sharp.
不，傑克，讓他講 那個小子，他很聰明
Yeah, he's playing you.
其實他在耍你
He's sharper than you are.
他比你聰明
He's telling you stories, right?
他在唬弄你，知道嗎？
He wants to be a good citizen.
他肯定對你說他要做一個好公民
Go to church.
要上教堂
Buy his mother a house.
要為她母親買房子
But he has spent more than half his life in prison.
但實際上他一生大部分的時間都在監獄裡
Two hours ago, he was sitting in a cell for weapons possession.
兩個小時前 他還因為非法持械被捕
- He's always gonna do what he has done. - I wasrt...
- 他不會改變了 - 我沒有...
He is a career criminal. That's who you're protecting.
他是一個職業罪犯，而你卻在保護他
- You all right? - Yeah. Frank's got him on the other side.
- 你還好麼？ - 嗯，弗蘭克在另外一邊對付他
He's got my gun too.
我的槍也被他搶了
Now, if you can't see how wrong this is...
如果到現在，你都還執迷不悟的話...
...I promise you I will speak from my heart...
我只能這樣說
...when I give the eulogy at your funeral.
我會在你的葬禮上為你念悼詞
So...
所以
...do you believe the kid?
你相信那小子？
Or do you believe your ex-partner?
還是相信你的前拍檔？
Frank, we're right on the other side of the door.
弗蘭克，我們就在門的另一邊
Because...
因為...
...if you believe the kid...
如果你相信他的話...
...you got a choice to make.
你必須做出選擇
Do you go through your ex-partner?
你要重新和你的搭檔一起工作？
Or do you choose door number two...
或者你選擇另一條路
...and go back to where you came, with your gimpy leg and your shot-up hand?
拖著你那條跛腿和受傷的手 繼續和我們作對
You're not gonna get very far. And what if your ex-partner is right, Jack?
你不會成功的 而且萬一我說的是正確的呢，傑克？
What if he is right, and you're wasting your whole miserable life?
如果我是正確的 那你做的這一切又是為了什麼呢?
- It's Frank. - You all right?
- 我是弗蘭克 - 你沒事吧？
Yeah. They're in the elevator. Seal the building.
我沒事，他們在電梯裡 封鎖整幢大樓
Come on, Bobby. Come on, get on that.
跟上，波比 快點，我們上去
Everybody out! Police!
警察，所有人出去！
Move, move! Police!
所有人出去！警察！ 快點，警察！
- Frank, where are you? - Bobby, I'm coming up!
- 弗蘭克，你在哪裡？ - 波比，我上來了！
All right. Come on, come on. Upstairs. Seal the stairwell.
好，快點 上樓，盯住樓梯間
- All right. - Find the back stairs. Check the roof.
- 好 - 你去逃生梯看看，檢查一下屋頂
- Come on, Mal! This way. - Got you.
- 快點！從這裡走 - 收到
- Maldonado, seal it up.
- 馬多納多， 守在這裡
Hello? Hello? Hello?
喂？喂？有人嗎？
- No, nothing. - No answer. He's not there. Come on.
- 沒人 - 沒有人回答，沒人在，我們走
I never open door.
我從不開門
Please. Please, help.
請，請幫幫我
Come on.
走吧
Jack, Jack, Jack. Thank you.
傑克，傑克，謝謝你
- Thank you. Thank you very much. - Thank you very much.
- 謝謝，太謝謝了 - 太謝謝你了
- You saw that, right? You heard him, right? - Yeah. He never opens the door.
- 你聽到他剛才所說的了，對嗎？ - 恩，他說他從不開門
Thank you very much, sir. Thank you.
太謝謝你了，先生，謝謝你
- Thank you. Thank you very much, sir. - Thank you.
- 謝謝你，太謝謝你了，先生 - 謝謝你
- You heard him, right, Jack? - Not now, Eddie.
- 你聽到他說的他從不開門的，對吧？ - 知道了，愛迪
- Keep your voice down. - He said he never opens the door.
- 小聲點 - 他說他從不開門
You know what that mean, right?
你知道這意味著什麼，對嗎？
Not right now. There's the signs everywhere.
希望這不是壞的兆頭
- Yeah, ADA MacDonald, please. - May I tell her who's calling?
- 喂，請讓副檢察官馬克當娜聽電話 - 請問是誰打來的
Yeah, tell her it's the guy that's got her witness.
嗯，告訴她我是負責護送她的證人的
You're driving a car during a hurricane.
你在颶風中開車
Like:
就是這個
A hurricane.
颶風
And there's three people at a bus stop.
路邊站有三個人
- A old woman. - Yeah.
- 一個老婦人 - 嗯
A friend, like my friend here.
另外一個是你的朋友，就像我倆
Him. He save your life, your friend.
你的這位朋友曾經救了你一命
It's Detective Mosley for you.
莫斯裡探員打來的電話
- Mosley? - Yeah?
- 莫斯裡？ - 喂？
Where are you? Where's my witness?
你在哪裡？我的證人在哪裡？
I'm about seven blocks from you.
我大約離你有七個街區
But there's about a ton of cops between me and you.
但滿街都是警察
And they all want this kid dead.
他們每個人都想想要這小子的命
Not to mention that you got a leak in your office.
況且還有你辦公室裡面的一個奸細
- Somebody's talking to these cops. - Shit.
- 不斷地向這些警察走漏風聲 - 該死
What did you think was gonna happen when you pinched Shue?
你當初起訴舒警官的時候 你就應該考慮到這些
You thought they'd just lay down and go away quietly?
你以為他們就束手就擒了？
We thought if we went to the grand jury, Shue would fold.
我以為如果我們求助於大陪審團 舒會說出實情
He bent but didn't break.
但他只是表面上妥協了
We were gonna throw it away until we ran into Edward Bunker last night.
如果不是昨天晚上，我們發現了愛德華本克 我們已經放棄了
Jury's tenure ends at 10. Without that kid, they'll vote no bill and it all goes away.
陪審團最晚能待到10點，沒有那小子 他們不會立案
He's an eyewitness. He makes this work.
他是目擊證人 是整個案子的關鍵
Where are you? I'll send my squad. Richard, pen.
你在哪裡？我派我的人過來 理查得，給我一支筆
What room?
那個房間？
- So, what, are they coming? - Yeah, they're coming.
- 怎麼樣，他們來嗎？ - 嗯，他們要來
Good. Because I gotta be somewhere, man. I got something to do.
太好了，庭審結束後我還有一個約會
I gotta be someplace by noon. I gotta go get something.
我得在中午之前到那裡 我一定不能失約的
It's real important.
因為這是個很重要的約會
- Oh, shit. - Yeah.
天哪
Ortiz, I'm coming in the building.
奧蒂斯，我進來了
Frank?
弗蘭克？
- Touhey and Kaller are taken care of. - Good. Find Bobby. He's on the back stairs.
- 圖西和凱樂沒事了 - 很好，去找波比，他在逃生梯那裡
Eddie, come here, put this on. Here, come on, put that on.
愛迪，過來，穿上這個 快點，穿上它
But it's a big, hot, wool shirt. It's hot. It's summer.
這是羊毛襯衫 太熱了，現在是夏天
- You're dressed like a criminal. - Oh, you want me to...?
- 你穿的是囚衣 - 哦，你想讓我換衣服？
You want me to change my...? I get it. But why can't I put that on?
我明白了，但我想試試那件
- What about this? - What about that?
- 這件怎麼樣？ - 那件怎麼了？
- What's wrong with this? It's just a pattern. - He don't even wear that.
- 這件哪裡不好了？你不喜歡它的樣式？ - 這件太古怪了
Just put the... Here.
讓你不要穿這件，別說了
Never mind. What about this?
好吧，那這件怎麼樣？
Is this all right? Mass-transit blue?
這件還行吧？普通的藍色？
When I was locked up, they had me work in the kitchen.
我以前蹲監獄的時候 我曾在廚房工作
So one day a little dude walk up to me and say:
有一天一個人過來跟我說
"Hey, you think you could bake me a cake?"
"嗨，你能幫我做一個蛋糕嗎，我女兒生日"
I said, "Yeah, I'll bake you a cake."
我說，"好，可以啊"
I ain't tell him I ain't never baked a cake, you know.
你知道嗎，那之前我從沒做過蛋糕
But I ain't got shit else to do.
我想反正我也沒事情
So, you know, I read the instructions...
所以，我就照著食譜
...I bake him a cake, you know, for his daughter's birthday.
給他做了一個蛋糕
She'd come up there to visit him.
後來她女兒來探望他，他把這個蛋糕給她
You know, it say, "Happy Birthday, Angel," right?
蛋糕上寫著，"生日快樂，天使"
He go crazy. He can't get enough, you know.
你不知道他有多感激我
He said, "Eddie, you done hooked me up. Man, you the man."
他說，"愛迪，你太棒了！"
And I started doing that. It was good. I had a skill.
從那以後我就一發不可收拾
People look at me different. They would start...
人們開始尊重我，他們開始...
- You missed a button. - Did I?
- 你少扣了一個扣子 - 是嗎？
Your buttons are all crooked.
你的扣子全扣歪了
- Come on. Come on, man. - All right.
- 快點，夥計 - 好的
Nugent.
紐金
You're a prince.
真有你的
- The word is 5E, boys, 5E. - Got it.
- 房間是5E，夥計們，5E. - 收到
Then I start doing my research, doing my due diligence.
然後我開始鑽研做蛋糕的技巧
I found out, you know, it's good money in birthday cakes for kids, you know.
而且開一個專門做生日蛋糕的店 能賺不少錢
That type of thing, like Tweety Bird or Bugs Bunny or something like that.
你可以把蛋糕做成各種動物的形狀
Or Yu-Gi-Oh! You ever heard of Yu-Gi-Oh!?
還有卡通人物雨果！ 你聽過麼？
- Yu-Gi-Oh! - Yu-Gi-Oh! Kids love that, man.
- 雨果！ - 雨果！小孩子們都喜歡那個
You don't know Yu-Gi-Oh!? You gotta get out more. Yu-Gi-Oh! Hot.
你不知道雨果！？ 你不知道他有多受歡迎
Know what I'm saying?
聽到了麼？
I'm gonna make money, Jack. Open up my bakery.
我會賺大錢的，傑克 經營我自己的糕點店
You gonna eat your words about me, Jack. How do I look? Do I look all right?
你會收回你之前對我說的話，傑克 我看上去怎麼樣？還不錯吧？
- All right. - Freeze! Police!
- 好 - 不許動！警察！
- Police! Police! - Shut up!
- 警察！警察！ - 閉嘴！
- Oh, my God!
- 噢，天哪！ - 閉嘴
Frank, they gave us the wrong apartment.
弗蘭克，不是這個房間
Put it down.
放下槍
Can't get lucky all the time.
你不會每次都那麼走運的
You can be smart every day, though.
但你幹嘛不聰明點呢？
- All right, give me the gun. - Hold on.
- 好了，把槍給我 - 等等
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
This place is crawling with cops, Eddie.
這裡全都是警察，愛迪
Hey, look at me.
嗨，看著我
Eddie, what are you doing?
愛迪，你要幹什麼？
How does it feel?
這種感覺如何？
You're a baker, right?
你還要開糕點店對吧？
Eddie, listen to him.
愛迪，你聽我說
Pull that trigger, you go to jail for life.
你開了槍，這輩子你都會坐牢
Frank, we're on our way down.
弗蘭克，我們下來了
Frank, do you read me?
弗蘭克，你能聽見麼？
- You can't stop me, you understand? - Time to go.
- 你們阻止不了我 - 我們該走了
- You can't stop me.
- 走吧 - 你們阻止不了我
You gave him a loaded weapon?
你居然給他了一把槍
- Frank. - Bobby, get these things off me.
- 弗蘭克. - 波比，快把手銬解開
- Did he take your gun? - They went south. Get out of here.
- 他們拿你槍了麼？ - 他們朝南走了，快追他們
Ortiz! Ortiz, give me a piece. Give me a piece! Get over here.
奧蒂斯， 給我一把槍 快給我一把槍
Make a hole, make a hole. Come on, make a hole.
讓開，讓開，快讓開
Speak to me. Come on, somebody, speak to me.
有人麼？有人在麼？
Turn.
走這邊
- Excuse me! - Open up!
- 對不起 - 開門！
Keep moving. Go. Go, go, go.
開車，快
Oh, shit.
天哪
On the bus! Let's go.
他們在公共汽車上，我們快追
- Just keep driving. - What are you doing?
- 一直開，別停車， - 你幹嘛？
- I'm a cop. Lock the back door. - He's got a gun!
- 我是警察，把後門鎖上 - 他有槍！
No stops. Tell them to hang on to something, Eddie!
別停下 告訴他們抓緊了，愛迪!
Hang on! Don't worry, this man, he's a police officer.
別擔心，他是警察
- Everything is gonna be fine. - Hang on!
- 別擔心，一切都會好的 - 抓緊了
Everybody just hang on. Don't worry!
大家抓緊了，別慌張
Right, right, right! Go right!
右，右，向右轉
- What are you doing? - Stop this thing!
- 你們在幹什麼？ - 快把車停下！
Get down!
趴下！
Get away from the bus! Away from the bus!
到一邊去！離公共汽車遠點
Stay down! Stay down!
大家趴下，別動
Heads down!
把頭低下！
- Where the hell are you? - Construction site at Baxter.
- 你們在哪裡？ - 巴可士街的建築工地
He has hostages.
他劫持有人質
Let me go.
放了我吧
Listen!
大家聽著
Everybody, stand up. They're not gonna shoot you.
大家都站起來，他們不會向你們開槍的
Stand up in front of the windows.
站在玻璃前面
They won't shoot you. You, stay down. Stay down.
他們不會對你們開槍的 你，蹲下，別站起來
Fill in the blanks. Fill in the spots.
全部站在窗子那裡去，別留下縫隙
Scoot over, scoot over! That's it.
快點，快點，好的，就是這樣
- All right, get Gruber down here. - Okay.
- 好吧，通知古博上尉 - 好的
Hey!
喂！
All right, seal off that end.
把那個出口封鎖了
- It's a busload. - Jesus, this shit just gets deeper.
- 公共汽車上全是人 - 天哪，這下越搞越大了
- Bobby? - Gruber's on his way.
- 波比? - 古博馬上就到
All right. We gotta get our stories straight, all right?
好吧，我們要口徑一致
We're getting our stories straight?
口徑一致，知道了麼？
Yeah, suit up.
把防彈背心穿上
Thought we could handle this quickly and quietly, commissioner.
局長，這件事何必勞您大駕？
A guy shoots a cop, takes a grand-jury witness hostage...
這個人朝警察開槍，還把一個大陪審團的證人劫為人質
...and we're supposed to make nice?
我們不能對他客氣了
Commissioner, look, sir, this is... Watch your back, sir.
局長，這...當心車門
This is my fault, all right?
這完全是我的錯
I used to work with Mosley, so I asked the captain to let me handle it.
我和莫斯裡原來是拍檔， 所以我讓警長把這這個案子交給我
I felt that I could bring him in. I just didn't realize how far gone he was.
我認為我可以捉住他， 但我沒想到他會這樣
- Stay on Tac 2, boys. - Wait for command, here we go.
- 隨時待命，弟兄們 - 隨時待命，好的
That's it, cover them up.
好的，把窗子蒙上
Good, okay. Great job. Thank you.
非常好，謝謝你們
- Commissioner, sir. Captain. - Hi, Mike.
- 局長，警長，你們好 - 邁克
- What do we got? - Cop. Twenty plus, flipped.
- 情況如何？ - 嫌犯是一個警察，車上有20多人，這人是個瘋子
- Suicidal? - Been to the farm twice the last four years.
- 他有自殺傾向？ - 過去四年他接受了兩次心理治療
- Twice? - Twice. Nothing like this, though.
- 兩次？ - 兩次，但都沒有這次這麼極端
- What do you know, detective? - Like the captain said, he flipped.
- 你的看法呢，偵探？ - 跟警長說的一樣，他是個瘋子
After he nailed Shue, he started spouting crap about making headlines.
他向舒開槍後，叫囂要上頭條
There's no way that you're getting this guy out.
這人相當的頑固
Please fall back behind the barricades. On the sidewalk.
請站到警戒線後面去，到人行道上去
Smart cop.
這是個很聰明的傢伙
Okay. You're all gonna be okay. We're gonna get you out of here.
好吧，你們都會沒事的 我們馬上放你們走
- Please, just move to the back of the bus. - Jack?
- 請到車的尾部去 - 傑克?
Just move to the back of the bus, please, right now.
請走到車的尾部去，現在
It's okay. You're gonna get off the bus. I am a police officer.
你們放心好了，我是一個警察
Jack, it's Mike Sheehan from HNT.
傑克，我是談判專家邁克.希恩
We worked that barricade deal on the concourse a few years ago.
我們幾年前還共事過
I'm gonna put this thing down, okay?
讓我把這個擴音器放下
- I'm sorry. - Jack!
- 對不起 - 傑克!
I'm sorry that I got you in this situation.
對不起，我給大家帶來這些麻煩
You know the drill, no weapons.
你很熟悉這一套了，我沒帶武器
Listen, you're on the job.
聽著，我只是公事公辦
- Just keep your head down. - You know the deal.
- 把頭放底點 - 你都知道這些步驟了
I'm just gonna step in here, nice and easy...
我靠近一些了
...and hand you this phone so we can talk, okay?
我會把這個電話給你，然後我們就可以開始談判
Make sure we got no injuries in there. Jack, just open the door, okay?
千萬不要傷害人質 傑克，把門打開吧
- I need to... - Just throw it, Mike!
- 我需要... - 扔過來好了，邁克！
- Okay, you got it. - Throw it!
- 好的 - 扔過來！
Here you go. Jack...
接著，傑克
Jack, can you hear me?
傑克，聽到了麼？
How many people you got in there, Jack?
車上有多少人？
Count how many people are here.
數數有多少人
Everybody put your hands up, please.
大家把手舉起來，謝謝
N. Y.P.D., we got a situation here. We need you people back on the sidewalk.
我們紐約警局，我們在執行公務 請大家回到人行道上去
- Stay behind the barricade. - Twenty-six, 28. Okay, thank you.
- 不要越過路障 - 26，28個，好的，謝謝
That's everybody? Please, don't cry, don't cry.
這就是所有的人了？ 請不要哭，不要哭
Everything's gonna be all right, just relax. Stay calm, okay? Thank you.
沒事的，不要驚慌 冷靜點，好麼？謝謝
- What is it? - Thirty-one. Thirty-one.
- 多少？ - 31
Okay, we have about 40 people on the bus.
好吧，這裡大概有40人
Okay, that's good.
好的
You know, it's important that we're clear with each other, Jack.
傑克，我對你直說好了
ESU and HNT are in place.
特警隊和人質談判小組都在這裡
The block is sealed, Jack. It's a frozen zone.
整個街區都被封鎖了，傑克
So let's work this out so everybody can go home, all right?
我們好好處理這件事情， 這樣大家都好下台
That's all we wanna do. Just end it, nice and easy.
這樣對大家都好
Jack?
傑克？
Jack? This is as far as you go, buddy.
傑克？你還想怎麼樣，老兄？
Keep talk...
說話啊...
- Is everybody okay? - Yeah.
- 大家還好吧？ - 嗯
- Hi, how are you? - Good.
- 你好，你怎麼樣了？ - 很好
How are you?
你呢？
My name's Eddie. Hi, how you doing? Everybody's okay?
我們名字叫愛迪 大家都還好？
What's your name?
你叫什麼名字？
- Christina.
- 克裡斯蒂納
That's a pretty name. How old are you, Christina?
那是個很漂亮的名字 你多大了？
- Seven. - Seven years old.
- 七歲 - 七歲了
And my strawberry recipe... I know I got one. Let me see.
我要給你做個草莓蛋糕 我知道怎麼做，讓我找找
Where's my strawberry recipe? Let's see.
我的草莓蛋糕呢？讓我看看
Angel-food-cake recipe right here.
這是怎麼做天使蛋糕
Here we go, strawberry fan.
找到了，草莓蛋糕！
See right here on the top?
看這個蛋糕的樣子
I can put a fan on the top.
我可以把它做成扇子的樣子
You know, like a Chinese fan?
就是一個中國扇子的樣子
I could do that.
我可以把蛋糕做成那樣
Whers your birthday?
你什麼時候生日？
- September 22nd. - Oh, so that's soon.
- 9月22日 - 哦，那很快了嘛
Gonna be 8 years old, huh? That's gonna be a good day for you.
就快8歲了，對吧？ 那是個很好的日子
Whers your birthday?
你的生日呢？
Today, actually.
今天，實際上
- Yeah. - Happy birthday to you.
- 是啊 - 祝你生日快樂
And, yeah, every day is somebody's birthday, you know.
是啊，每天都有人過生日
That's gonna be the motto for my shop:
我將來糕點店的標語就會是這個：
"Every day's a birthday," you know.
「每一天都是一個生日」
I didn't know my birthday was gonna turn out like this, but...
沒想到在我的生日會發生這樣的事情，可是...
Yeah, I'm glad to be, you know, here, alive, you know.
至少我還活著，我已經很高興了
- Right here, Jack. - Yeah, Sheehan.
- 說吧，傑克 - 希恩
Commissioner, sir.
局長
- Sheehan? - Right here.
- 希恩? - 說吧
All right. This is what I want.
好吧，這是我的條件
I want you to get me Assistant District Attorney MacDonald...
我要你幫我接通副檢察官馬克當娜
...a court stenographer and somebody from TV.
還有一位法庭書記員，和一位記者
Somebody that I would recognize.
我認識的記者
I want them to come on the bus and record sworn testimony.
我要他們到車上來 幫我錄一段證詞
When I get what I want, I'll let everybody out. Safely.
這完了後，我會讓每個人安全地離開
- That's a tall order. It'll take some time... - Just do it. I'm not in the mood, okay?
- 我需要一些時間 - 別跟我來這一套
Get these people here in 15 minutes...
15分鐘之類讓他們到這裡來
...or I'm gonna shoot these passengers one at a time...
否則我會開始向乘客開槍
...and throw them out the door. - Jack, be cool, okay?
- 然後把他們的屍體扔到車外 - 傑克，冷靜點
Let's not do anything rash. This thing can end without bloodshed.
別衝動，這件事情可以和平解決
- Okay? We can work this... - Fifteen minutes.
- 一切好商量，好麼？ - 15分鐘
Jack? Jack?
傑克？傑克？
He's gone.
他掛了
All right, everybody on your feet.
好吧，大家都站起來
- Jack, what are you doing? - Gotta get these people off this bus.
- 傑克，你幹什麼？ - 我得讓這些人下去
But you just made your call. You called the DA. They said they'd come.
你不是才打了電話麼？ 你讓檢察官來，他們不是同意了麼？
- Everybody's coming. - Nobody's coming, okay?
- 這些人都會來的 - 沒人會來的，知道麼？
What do you mean, nobody's coming?
沒人會來？為什麼？
They're gonna breach this bus in less than five minutes.
5分鐘內，他們會強行進攻這個巴士
- They're gonna kill me, kill you... - Jack, what about testifying?
- 他們會殺了我，殺了你 - 傑克，我還要作證呢？
We're right here. We can go. We can end this.
我們應該在這裡等他們來 然後一切都會結束
- We can testify. - Nobody's testifying.
- 我們等他們來，然後作證 - 不會有人作證
It's all over, Eddie.
一切都完了，愛迪
We lose, kid.
我們輸了
- Hey, Ray. - Frank.
- 雷 - 弗蘭克.
You...?
你們...?
You guys going in?
你們要進攻了？
The commissioner hasn't given us the green light yet.
局長還沒有下命令
Well, I don't need to remind you that he shot two of us.
嗯，我要提醒你，他殺了兩個警察
Enough said.
我知道該怎麼做了
We got maybe 40 civilians on that bus. Get them out.
車上有40個平民 把他們救出來
I don't want anybody hurt, including our guys.
不能讓任何人受傷， 包括我們自己的人
Nobody's gonna get hurt, commissioner. These guys know what to do.
局長，沒有人會受傷的 我們的突擊隊員都是訓練有素的
- We have movement. - Let's move in.
- 有情況出現 - 大家注意了
- Hold your fire. Repeat, hold your fire. - Move in to the bus. Let's go.
- 不要開槍，重複，不要開槍 - 朝汽車靠近，行動
Hey. What...?
喂，怎麼了？
Bob.
鮑勃.
When you get outside...
你出去的時候
- Happy birthday. - Thank you.
- 生日快樂 - 謝謝
They'll take you to a holding area. It'll be hectic.
他們會把你帶到一個隔離區 那裡會很混亂
- But everybody's out there... - Listen to me, listen to me.
- 可是要是人人都出去了... - 聽我說，你聽我說
Once you get outside that perimeter, you just get lost.
你一旦離開了這個封鎖區 你便可以逃走
- What if they...? - Keep moving. You just keep moving.
- 可是如果他們？ - 不要停下，你一定不要停下
Come here. You look great.
聽我說，你看起來不錯
Hey, gray suit.
喂，灰色西裝哦
Got you a gray suit.
這可是你要的灰色西裝
All right? Hands in the air, folks. Don't look back.
好了，大家把手舉在頭上，別回頭
Hands in the air, you'll be all right. You'll be all right.
手舉在頭上，都結束了，結束了
Next. Sorry.
下一位，對不起
Come on, come on, let's go!
快，快，跟我來
- What is he doing? - How should I know?
- 他這是在做什麼？ - 我怎麼知道？
- I'll let you know when I know. - Don't you...
- 我現在不知道 - 你居然用這種口氣...
I'll let you know when I know. Out of my face!
我明白了自然會告訴你 滾開！
Kaller, give me a hand with them!
凱樂，過來幫幫我
Bobby? Right there. Right here.
波比?這邊，這邊
- That's him. That's him. - Hey, man!
- 就是他 - 喂，你幹嘛？
- It's not him. - Let him go.
- 不是他 - 讓他走吧
- The dude, he changed. It's not me. - What?
- 他穿了別人的衣服 - 什麼？
- He's in a suit, a gray suit. - Suit, gray suit.
- 他換上了一套西裝，灰色西裝 - 灰色西裝，好的
- We count 31. - That leaves eight people on the bus.
- 有31人下了車 - 那車上還有8個人
No, I was the last one off the bus.
不，我是最後一個人
The only person left on that bus is the guy with the gun.
車上就只剩下那個拿槍的人
- Then go, do it! - Let's go, let's go.
- 那你們行動吧 - 開始行動
- Get your people out there. Let's go. - Come on, let's go.
行動開始
Mosley is still on the bus. That kid is here somewhere. We checked...
莫斯裡還在車上 那個小子不在車上，我們搜查了...
Bobby, I don't care what you checked.
波比，別廢話了
Check it again, now. Go. You guys, that way.
再給我搜一遍，馬上 你們，去那邊
This is Detective Jack Mosley. Shield number 227.
我是警探傑克 莫斯裡，警號227
I guess this will be my last will and testament.
這可能會是我最後的遺囑
Don't shoot!
別開槍！
Do not shoot! Do not shoot!
別開槍！別開槍！
- Who is that? - Hold your fire!
- 那個人是誰？ - 別開槍！
- Is it that wit from the 32?
- 那個人就是那個證人麼？
Get on your goddamn radio. Find out who that is.
給我查清楚那個人是誰
Guns down, hold your fire!
別開槍！
- Do not move! Step away from the bus! - Don't shoot, hold your fire!
- 站住！不要靠近那部汽車！ - 別開槍！
- Do not shoot! - Get away from the bus!
- 離開公共汽車！
Hold your fire.
別開槍
Jack. Jack, it's me. Jack Mosley!
傑克，是我
It's me, Eddie, Jack.
傑克，是我，愛迪
Chuck Berry.
查克.貝裡
Chuck Berry, he got locked up for armed robbery.
查克.貝裡， 他因為搶劫入獄
He changed. He changed.
但是他後來改變了
Barry White, he stole 300 tires.
巴裡.懷特，他偷了300各輪胎
Can you picture big Barry White stealing 300 tires? He changed.
你能想像他偷了300個輪胎麼？他後來也變了
You said... You said people don't change.
你說...你說人本性難移
- People change. - Eddie.
- 但是實際上人會變的 - 愛迪
- What? - You're killing me.
- 怎麼了？ - 你把我害死了
Team three, breach the bus. Repeat, team three, breach the bus.
第三組，行動 重複，第三組，行動
Entrance team moving in.
第三組靠近汽車
Get out of the way!
讓開！
Head down! Cover your ears and your eyes!
把頭埋下！ 遮住耳朵和眼睛！
- Hold fire. - Go, go!
- 別開槍 - 跟進，跟進！
- Go, go, go! - Hold your fire!
- 跟進！ - 別開槍！
This is a nightmare.
他到底要幹嘛？
Hold fire!
別開槍！
- Let's go! Move, move, move! - Stay down!
- 快點！行動！ - 當心！
- Move up! Move up! - Come here.
- 過來，過來！ - 這裡
Team two, status?
第二組，報告你們情況？
Go ahead! Take it! Go!
快！
The bus is empty.
車上沒有人
They went through the bus doors!
他們從前門逃跑了！
They're in the goddamn building! Seal it off!
他們在這棟樓裡！ 封鎖這裡！
- All clear. The bus is empty. - They've entered the building.
- 汽車上沒有人 - 他們跑進了樓裡
Seal the building, start a search.
封鎖這棟樓，開始搜索
Remember, heads up. He just shot two cops. Be careful.
當心，他殺了兩個警察，你們要小心
Jack, I gotta tell you something.
傑克，我要告訴你一件事情
Hey, man. Jack, listen to me, man.
喂，傑克，聽我說
Jack, I wanna tell you something.
傑克，我要給你說件事情
Hold on, hold on, wait. I gotta tell you something. It's important.
等等，我告訴你件事情 這很重要
Shit. Get up, go.
振作點，我們走
Oh, shit.
媽的
Hey, sir. I'm a cop, all right? I'm on the job.
對不起，這位先生，我是一個警察 我在執行任務
Look, I need that phone for a minute.
我借你的電話用下
Look what you did to my suit, man.
看看你把我的西裝弄成這樣了
I told you you was gonna get me shot.
我就知道你會讓我中彈的
It's me. I need your help.
是我，我需要你的幫助
All this started because my friend Maurice came by my house.
一切都是因為我朋友毛裡斯
Two days ago,
兩天前他到我家來
He all excited.
他那時很慌張
He got a shoebox.
他手裡拿著一個鞋盒
He had a gun.
他有把槍
He talking about, "Hold this for me for a little while."
他對我說，「你幫我保管一陣子」
I'm like, "I'm on parole." He like, "Me too."
我對他說，「我還在緩刑期內呢」 他說，「我也是」
Next day, somebody shot him.
過了一天，他被殺了
Thirty-two thousand dollars in that shoebox.
鞋盒裡面有三萬兩千塊錢
- That's a sign, huh? - Yeah.
- 那是個凶兆，對吧 - 是的
It's a very big sign.
那真是個凶兆
Easy, easy, easy.
當心
You know how much it gonna take me to open the bakery?
你知道開個糕點店需要多少錢麼？
Thirty-one thousand dollars.
三萬一千塊錢
Jack, I got so nervous I ran out the house.
傑克，當時我不知道怎麼辦 我就衝出房外
I went to Port Authority and I put the money in a locker.
把這些錢藏在了汽車站的儲物櫃裡
I get back to my house...
當我回家的時候
...my parole officer's there...
我的緩刑輔導員在那裡
...in my house.
就在我家裡
He got Maurice's gun in his hand.
他發現了毛裡斯留下的槍
He looking at me like, "That's it, Eddie."
他看著我，很失望的樣子
And he's talking about 15 years, man.
他說這至少得判15年
I got so sick.
我嚇呆了
Then the DA came to my cell...
後來檢察官給我打來電話
...and he showed me the picture of that cop.
他給我看了那個警察的照片
Then I met you.
然後就是你
Jack, they clean them lockers out every 24 hours.
傑克， 每天他們都要清理那些儲物櫃
I had a little schedule going, man.
我的時間還挺緊的
Court at 10:00...
10點鐘上法庭作證
...Port Authority at 12.
12點趕到汽車站
Hey. Hey, look at me. Wake up.
喂，看著我，清醒點
You ain't gonna die on me, are you?
你不會在我面前死去，對麼？
I don't know, I never died before.
我怎麼知道，我從來沒有經歷過死亡
It's not gonna happen today.
你今天不會死的
Hey. Thank you for coming.
謝謝你來這裡
- What's going on? - Look. Shot here. I think it went in and out.
- 出什麼事情了？ - 你看，他這裡中槍了
Yeah, let's get him in.
好吧，我們把他抬到車上去
I know you.
我認識你
- Come on. - I was at your house.
- 來吧 - 我去過你家
- You were at my apartment? - Had to get my gun.
- 你去過我家？ - 我得把我槍帶上
Bigmouth.
別說話了
It was very nice, very clean.
你的房間很漂亮，很乾淨
The police grilled me for an hour at the hospital.
警察在醫院盤問了我一個小時
What'd you say to them?
你對他們說了什麼？
That you're a self-medicating, depressed individual.
我說你是個抑鬱症患者
And you don't care about anything or anyone.
我說你什麼都能幹得出來
Oh, she's honest, straightforward. That's sexy. I like that.
她好坦率 這樣很性感，我喜歡這樣
What'd you do this time, Jack?
這次你又準備怎麼做，傑克？
He saved my life a couple times.
他幾次都救了我的命
Hey, he's a good dude. You gotta give him another chance.
他是個好人 你應該再給他一次機會
I don't know what he did, but you gotta give him another chance.
我不知道他以前做了什麼， 但是你應該再給他一次機會
He gotta have somebody to talk to.
他需要一個談話的人
I'm not gonna be around.
我可不能一直陪他
- Eddie, this is my sister, Diane. - What?
- 愛迪，這是我妹妹，戴安. - 什麼？
She's your sister?
她是你妹妹？
Oh, man.
原來如此
I just started having a little hope for you. Your family don't even like you.
我才開始對你有了好感 可是你的家人都不喜歡你
I got a sister too.
我也有一個妹妹
But she live in Seattle.
但是她在西雅圖
I was supposed to go out there and start my bakery.
我本來打算去那裡開我的糕點店的
I was supposed to go out there today to see her.
我本來今天就該出發的
See her on the bus.
她說到汽車站來接我的
I can stop the bleeding...
我現在把血止住了
...but he's gotta get stitched up, get to a hospital.
但是我們必須到醫院去 把傷口給他縫上
We gotta be at the courthouse in less than 20.
我們需要在20分鐘內到法庭上去
You're gonna have to do it.
你必須得幫助我
You're gonna be fine, Eddie. It's not as bad as it looks.
一切都會好的，愛迪. 這不像看上去的那麼糟糕
What happened to your hand?
你的手怎麼了？
I gotta ask you one more favor.
看來你還得幫我個忙
Just a little favor.
很小的忙
Hey, is today really your birthday?
喂，今天真的是你的生日？
No.
不是
No, I just said that because the little girl, she was so scared.
我說今天是我的生日 因為我不想小女孩那麼害怕
She was cute, man.
她很可愛
Whers your birthday?
你生日是多久？
- I don't know. - What do you mean, you don't know?
- 我不知道 - 你不知道是什麼意思？
No, for real, I don't know.
真的，我不知道
I'm not... I came up in foster care. Had a lot of birthdays.
我是在孤兒院長大的 那裡太多的生日了
But didn't you say...? You got a sister, right? That you're going to see?
但是你說有一個妹妹？你今天要去見的
Yeah, I just found out about her a couple months ago.
是啊，我幾個月前才發現
- Never met your sister? - No.
- 你見過她麼？ - 沒有
That's why I'm going out to Seattle to meet her.
那也是我去西雅圖的原因，我想見她
I'm looking forward.
我很期待
Maybe she turns out to look like Angelina Jolie.
說不定她長得像安吉麗娜.朱麗呢
Shit, if she do, I hope she ain't my sister.
我可不希望她只是我妹妹
Hey, man, what you want on your cake, man?
你想要蛋糕上寫什麼字？
You never told me. I gotta send you one, man.
我會給你做一個蛋糕的
- I don't want no cake, Eddie. - Damn it, Jack, come on, man...
- 我不需要什麼蛋糕，愛迪. - 別這麼不給面子，老兄
I can't think of anything that has happened in my life...
我想不起...
...that I would want written on a cake. - Nothing?
- 有什麼我想寫在蛋糕上面的 - 一句話都沒有？
I'm not a good guy, Eddie.
我不是一個好人，愛迪.
I'm not a good guy.
我不是一個好人
Yeah, me neither.
好吧，那我也不是
- Diane. - Frank.
- 戴安 - 弗蘭克
Give me the keys.
把鑰匙給我
- Stay in the car. - Little out of your sector, aren't you?
- 呆在車裡別出來 - 這裡可不是你的轄區，不是麼？
Saving lives knows no bounds.
救命可不分什麼轄區
- You should know that, Frank. - You look good.
- 這你應該很清楚， 弗蘭克. - 你看上去氣色不錯嘛
You look a little desperate. Doesrt suit you.
你看上去有點絕望 這可不像你
Open the door.
把門打開
Open the door. Open the door.
快把門打開
Sorry, Jack, this is as close as I can get you.
對不起，傑克，我就只能送你到這裡了
Like I said, you're looking good.
好吧，算你走運
Thanks, kid.
謝謝了，兄弟
All right, come on, let's go.
好吧，我們去法庭上
No, hey, hold on. Hold on a minute.
不，等下
Why is that? Hold on for what?
為什麼？還等什麼？
This is as far as you go too.
你就到這裡為止了
- Come on, man. I don't... - Listen to me, Eddie.
- 什麼意思？ - 聽我說，愛迪
- What? - Listen.
- 怎麼了？ - 聽著
Those guys you were gonna testify against...
你要去指證的這些人
...those cops? - Yeah?
- 這些警察 - 嗯？
I was one of them.
我就是其中一個
You were gonna testify against me too.
也就是說，你要去指證我
I did what they did.
他們做的，我都做了
We did some bad things.
我知道那很壞
I did another bad thing when I used you.
我利用了你
I was gonna let you do what I should have done.
其實根本不需要你來指證我們
What I should have had the courage to do six years ago.
我若干年前就應該自首了
I'm sorry.
對不起
You know, if you didn't come to get me today...
你知道，要是今天不是你的話
...l'd be dead right now.
我現在已經死了
- Right. - So...
- 恩 - 所以...
I was supposed to meet you.
今天我們見面
That was the sign.
是命中注定
You saved my life, kid.
你救了我一命
Take care of yourself, kid.
保重了
Thank you.
謝謝你
Make cakes, Eddie the baker.
你可以做糕點了，愛迪師傅
Oh, yeah. You give the car keys to your best friend.
哦對了，你把車鑰匙交給你的朋友
You let him take the old lady to the hospital.
你讓他帶老婦人去醫院
You stay at the bus stop with the girl because she's the girl of your dreams, right?
你在車站等那個夢中的女孩，對麼？
So everything's gonna be okay.
所以一切都會好的
- Right? - Yeah.
- 對吧？ - 嗯
Have fun in Seattle. Say hi to your sister.
西雅圖生活愉快！向你妹妹問好
Yeah.
好的
Get him to the Port Authority. Make sure he gets on that bus.
你載他去汽車站 保證他趕上那班車
- Carl, thanks. - No problem.
- 卡爾，多謝了 - 不用
All right.
好的
Hell of a morning, huh?
真是糟糕的一個早上，對吧？
Where's the wit?
那小子呢？
You're looking at him.
他不在了
I let the kid go, Frank.
我放他走了，弗蘭克
- You're not gonna get to him now. - Bullshit.
- 你抓不住他了 - 去你的
Wouldrt do that.
你幹什麼？
So...
那...
...what do you think you're gonna tell them?
你要在法庭上怎麼說？
Are you gonna tell them everything?
你要把所有的事情都說出來麼？
Are you gonna tell them about you too?
你要給他們說你也是一員麼？
You think that's gonna make you feel better?
你覺得那樣你良心就好受點了？
Nothing's gonna make me feel better.
我怎麼都不會好受點
Then why?
那你這是為什麼？
Look, Jack, you and me...
你聽我說，傑克，你和我...
...we did our business in a certain way.
我們一直就是這樣做事的
You never complained when we cleared the tough cases.
即使是那些很棘手的案子， 我們也心照不宣
It didn't bother you doing any of that until...
你以前什麼都無所謂，直到...
Listen to me, all right? You listen.
聽我說，好麼？聽我說
Okay, Jack? Really listen.
傑克，你聽好了
Whatever you think that you are gonna do up there...
你如果想在法庭上揭露真相
...it is never gonna happen.
我不會讓那發生的
You are not gonna make it.
你不會成功的
Is that what you're thinking, Frank?
你這樣想麼，弗蘭克？
You're gonna shoot me down here? Nobody knows?
你要在這裡殺了我？ 你以為沒人會知道？
Like the Ling family, huh?
就像你殺掉林家一樣？
Like they never knew.
你以為別人看不出來？
He was a stupid old man who wouldn't keep his mouth shut.
他是個傻老頭 他自己管不住自己的嘴巴
All right, so I stuck a gun in some guy's mouth.
好吧，是我把槍指到他嘴裡
- He had a heart attack, he died. So what? - So what?
- 然後他心臟病發作了死了，又怎樣? - 又怎樣？
Look, if it hadrt happened the way that it did, if he hadrt died...
你聽著，如果他沒有心臟病發，他沒有死...
...you would've been patting me on the back, saying, "Good job."
你當初就不會拍著我背說，「做得好」
Collateral damage, it is a fact of life in this business.
我們這一行，誤傷總是會發生的
He took his last breaths while you were wiping the fingerprints off the room.
你在房間裡清理指紋的時候，他還活著
- He was gonna take down our case. - He was an innocent man.
- 他不死我們就會完蛋 - 他是無辜的
- He was somebody's husband.
- 他是一個丈夫
- He was gonna take down our case. - He was somebody's father.
- 他不死我們就會完蛋 - 他是一位父親
He was gonna take down our case! What were we supposed to do?
他不死我們就會完蛋！ 我們不得不那樣做！
- He wanted to tell the truth. - Fuck the truth!
- 他只是想把真相說出來 - 去他媽的真相
Right.
好吧
I'm not gonna need this anymore.
我再也不需要這個了
Bobby? He's on his way up.
波比？他上來了
Take him out.
幹掉他
Mosley's in the building! Get the ADA. Freeze!
莫斯裡在這裡！快通知副檢察官 別動！
- Hands in the air! - Don't shoot.
- 舉起手來！ - 別開槍
- Don't move! Down on your knees. - I'm not armed.
- 別動！跪下！ - 我沒有武器
- Down on your knees! Now! - Don't shoot, I'm not armed.
- 跪下！馬上！ - 別開槍，我沒有武器
Lower your weapon. Just call ADA MacDonald, please, on the radio.
別用槍指著我 請通知副檢察官馬克當娜
- Hands up. - Get ADA MacDonald here right now!
- 手舉起來 - 讓副檢察官馬克當娜到這裡來，馬上！
- Don't shoot. Don't shoot me. - Get your hands up!
- 別開槍 - 把你的手舉起來！
Just get ADA MacDonald for me.
請讓副檢察官馬克當娜到這裡來
- Jack, come on! - I won't argue with you. Get down.
- 傑克，別耍花樣！ - 廢話少說，跪到地上！
Mosley! Mosley!
莫斯裡! 莫斯裡!
Hands up!
手舉起來！
Where's my witness? Where's Edward Bunker?
我的證人呢？ 愛德華.本克在哪裡去了？
He didn't make it.
他不能來了
I'm gonna take his place.
我代替他作證
- Please lower your weapons. - Hold your fire and stand down.
- 請不要把槍對著我 - 你們把槍放下
Back off.
你們讓開
I have information...
我有證據...
...regarding your ongoing witness-tampering investigation.
證明有人想殺害你目前這個案子的證人
Dates, cases that include extortion...
我還要提供證據 有關很多刑訊逼供的案件
...manslaughter and possible homicide...
傷害甚至謀殺證人
...involving members of the 14th Precinct.
這些案件涉及到14轄區的警察
These charges include Captain Dan Gruber...
涉案人員包括丹.古博上尉
...detectives Jerry Shue...
傑瑞.舒探員
...Edward Maldonado...
埃德華.麥多納多
...Bob Torres...
鮑博.托裡斯
...Jim Mulvey...
吉姆.馬利
...myself...
還有我自己
...and Detective Frank Nugent.
還有法蘭克.紐金探員
What's this about, Mosley? What do you want?
你說這些是為了什麼，莫斯裡？ 你想要做什麼？
I want Edward Bunker's record expunged.
我要還愛德華.本克一個清白
- Done. What else? - Nothing else.
- 可以，還有其他要求麼？ - 沒有了
You can substantiate all this, Mosley?
你可以證明你說的一切麼，莫斯裡？
Yeah.
是的
Gun!
槍！
Hold your fire. I fired that shot.
別開槍，是我開的那槍
You're gonna shoot me down here? Nobody knows?
你要在這裡殺了我？ 你以為沒人會知道？
Like the Ling family, huh?
就像你殺掉林家一樣？
Like they never knew.
你以為別人看不出來？
He was a stupid old man who wouldn't keep his mouth shut.
他是個傻老頭 他自己管不住自己的嘴巴
All right, so I stuck a gun in some guy's mouth.
好吧，是我把槍指到他嘴裡
- He had a heart attack, he died. So what? - So what?
- 然後他心臟病發作了死了，又怎樣？ - 又怎樣？
- So how about he was innocent?
- 你可知道他是一個無辜的人？
- Innocent? - How about he didn't deserve to die?
- 無辜？ - 他不該成為犧牲品
Look, if it hadrt happened the way that it did, if he hadrt died...
你聽著，如果他沒有心臟病發，他沒有死...
...you would've been patting me on the back, saying, "Good job."
你當初就不會拍著我背說，「做得好」
Collateral damage, it is a fact of life in this business.
我們這一行，誤傷總是會發生的
He took his last breaths while you were wiping the fingerprints off the room.
你在房間裡清理指紋的時候，他還活著
- He was gonna take down our case. - He was an innocent man.
- 他不死我們就會完蛋 - 他是無辜的
- He was somebody's husband.
- 他是一個丈夫
- He was gonna take down our case. - He was somebody's father.
- 他不死我們就會完蛋 - 他是一位父親
He was gonna take down our case! What were we supposed to do?
他不死我們就會完蛋！ 我們不得不那樣做！
- He wanted to tell the truth. - Fuck the truth!
- 他只是想把真相說出來 - 去他媽的真相
Let's get you to the jury.
我們帶你到法庭上去
- Thanks a lot. - Thanks.
- 謝謝
Okay.
好的
- Hey, happy birthday. - Happy birthday, Jack.
- 生日快樂 - 生日快樂，傑克
Welcome back, Jack.
歡迎回來，傑克
- Are you kidding me? - Two years in the pen is enough.
- 你什麼意思？ - 你在監獄裡呆了兩年，終於回來了
Thanks for that memory. Thank you.
那可不是一段好的回憶
- Happy birthday, Jack. - Happy birthday.
- 生日快樂，傑克 - 生日快樂
- Happy birthday. Blow them out. - Welcome home.
- 生日快樂，把蠟燭吹了吧 - 歡迎你回家
I hate birthdays, you know that, right?
我討厭生日，你們都知道的，對吧？
- Sorry, sorry. - Happy birthday.
- 對不起 - 生日快樂
This came with it.
這裡還有一封信
Dear Jack Mosley:
親愛的傑克.莫斯裡:
I hope you're doing well and everything worked out like it was supposed to.
我希望你一切都好
I'm doing great.
我很好
Seattle is different, and I like it a lot.
西雅圖同紐約不太一樣，但是我很喜歡這裡
I'm not sure I ever smelled fresh air before I got here. It's a trip.
我從來沒有呼吸過這麼新鮮的空氣 這就像一次旅遊
Sometimes I can't believe it. It's the best feeling I've had in my life.
有時我不敢相信，我現在的生活會是如此的美好
I'm busting my ass, but I'm happy, though.
雖然現在生活很忙碌，但是我很開心
The bakery is now open. Three cheers.
我的糕點店也開張了，哈哈
I put my name first because I'm doing all the hard work.
我的糕點店叫做「愛迪和傑克的糕點店」 我把我的名字放前面，因為主要是我在打理它
These ovens are hot, man.
烤箱很燙的，兄弟
Hope you like the cake. What did I tell you?
希望你喜歡這個蛋糕 我說過會給你做個蛋糕的
- That's Eddie. - Lf you're ever in town, you got a friend.
- 那是愛迪 - 如果你什麼時候到這裡來了，隨時找我好了
Thank you for doing the right thing, Jack Mosley. God bless you.
謝謝你為我做的一切，上帝保佑你，傑克.莫斯裡
Keep in touch. Peace.
保持聯繫
- That's great. - Go on, take one more. Look.
- 這太好了 - 再給我拍一張吧
You know how this guy...? I was talking, take one more.
你們知道這個人？ 我剛剛在說話，再來一張
Happy birthday, Jack.
生日快樂，傑克.